Lakshmi Priya

Senior Technical Writer

Lakshmi Priya

107, 8th Street, Kamaraj Colony, Chennai, India

Ph - +91 9884000186

Email - preeyasree@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/lakshmipriyapt

Summary

A seasoned technical writer with over 16 years of experience authoring diverse content tailored to diverse audiences. More than five years of experience in producing technical documentation aimed at enhancing internal developer experience.

Possesses a comprehensive background in both technical and business domains, enabling effective communication of product or service intricacies to a wide range of audiences.

I am a certified Agile Practitioner (PMI-ACP®)

Skills

Project Management

- Communication and Presentation
- Stakeholder Management
- Familiarity with Agile and Waterfall Methodologies
- Familiarity with JIRA

Authoring

- Markdown & Doc-as-code approach using static site generators like Jekyll to publish deliverables
- Microsoft® Word
- Adobe® Technical Communication Suite (FrameMaker, RoboHelp, and Acrobat 3D)
- MadCap® Flare
- Author-IT

Graphics Design Tools

- TechSmith SnagIt
- Microsoft® Visio,
- Paint

Programming Languages

Basic exposure to C, C++, and Python

Other Skills

Exposure to Git Bash, Postman, and Swagger (OpenAPI Spec)

Content Management System

- Microsoft® SharePoint
- WordPress
- Confluence

Version Control

- Bitbucket/GitHub
- Tortoise SVN

Experience

Senior Technical Writer / Trimble Inc, Chennai

Mar 2017 - PRESENT

- Created comprehensive developer references and technical instruction for core microservices.
- Facilitated stand up and replenishment meetings for the technical writing team.
- Prioritized responsibilities and tickets to meet deadlines.
- Contributed to the overall improvement of team methodologies, processes
- Implemented a doc-as-code approach with open-source static site generator Jekyll.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams and participated in project planning discussions and standup meetings.
- Communicated effectively to establish scope and requirements.
- Recommended design choices for linking API references and SDKs in the developer guide, managed internal communications for the suite of services, managed small-scale technical writing projects.
- Managed internal communications for the suite of services.
- Contributed to documenting team best practices and standard procedures.

Senior Technical Writer / Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai

Sep 2010 - Mar 2017

- Authored content for multiple documentation types such as mobile help, online help, user guide, installation guide, API reference guide, troubleshooting guide, tips and tricks guide, training materials, design documents, maintenance manuals, website content, read me, and release notes.
- Trained junior writers, led a team of writers for technical documentation projects.
- Evaluated and researched trends in technical writing.
- Reviewed documents authored by peers and junior writers.
- Evaluated competency levels of reports and trainees.
- Prepared project plans and estimation for documentation projects.
- Performed end-to-end project management activities.
- Worked on proposals and bid responses to effectively convey the company's strengths and qualifications to potential clients by working collaboratively with sales and business development teams.

Technical Communicator / Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2008 - Sep 2010

- Authored or updated documentation including user's guide, admin guide, online help, new features guide, troubleshooting guide, and Installation guide by strictly adhering to client writing standards.
- Reviewed application user interfaces for usability.
- Put together a communication strategy including creating mailers, presentations, and newsletters to foster engagement.
- Supported organization wide effort in reviewing technical documents for compliance initiatives.

Junior Technical Writer / Synaptris Decisions Pvt Ltd

Aug 2006 - Jan 2008

- Responsible for entire documentation development lifecycle for writing and maintaining single-sourced user guides
- Reviewed error messages.
- Peer reviewed documents for language, conformance to standards, clarity, and completeness.

Education

B.E. Mechanical Engineering / Institute of Road and Transport Technology

2001 - 2005